<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<resources>

    <string name="app_name">SRCMarineInfo1</string>
    <string name="hello_world">Hello world!</string>
    <string name="action_settings">Settings</string>
    <string name="help_string">Help</string>
    <string name="strBranch">USMC</string>
    <string name="MOSTitle"> <u>MOS Title</u>.</string>
    <string name="MOSRank"> <u>MOS Ranks</u>.</string>
    <string name="anim_first">First we showcase this…</string>
    <string name="anim_second">Then this…</string>
    <string name="anim_third">Finally this!</string>
    <string name="showcase_main_spinner_title">Navigation Spinner</string>
    <string name="showcase_main_spinner_message">Click this to navigate to the main areas of the app</string>
    <string name="showcase_main_rank_title">Swipe Left or Right</string>
    <string name="showcase_main_rank_message">The App is now displaying a set of screen in which you could view by swiping left or right.</string>
    <string name="showcase_button_ok">I understand</string>

    <string-array name="actions_array">
        <item>Ranks</item>
        <item>Military Time</item>
        <item>MOS/AFSC</item>
        <item>Alpha Numeric</item>
        <item>Org structure</item>
        <item>Acks</item>
    </string-array>

    <!-- Nav Drawer Menu Items -->
    <string-array name="nav_drawer_items">
        <item>Home</item>
        <item>Ranks</item>
        <item>Military Time</item>
        <item>MOS/AFSC</item>
        <item>Alpha Numeric</item>
        <item>Org structure</item>
        <item>Acks</item>
    </string-array>

    <!-- Nav Drawer List Item Icons -->
    <!-- Keep them in order as the titles are in -->
    <array name="nav_drawer_icons">
        <item>@drawable/home_icon</item>
        <item>@drawable/rank_icon</item>
        <item>@drawable/wallclock</item>
        <item>@drawable/patch</item>
        <item>@drawable/alpha</item>
        <item>@drawable/orgstructure</item>
        <item>@drawable/sunny</item>
    </array>

    <!-- Content Description -->
    <string name="desc_list_item_icon">Item Icon</string>
    <string name="hello_blank_fragment">Hello blank fragment</string>
    <string name="afsc_home_detail">The Army and Marine Corps call their enlisted jobs "MOS\'s," or "Military Occupation Specialties." The Navy and Coast Guard call their enlisted jobs "ratings." But, in the Air Force, enlisted jobs are known as "AFSCs," or "Air Force Specialty Codes." \n \n The Air Force divides their AFSCs (enlisted jobs) into the following overall categories: Operations, Maintenance &amp; Logistics, Support, Medical &amp; Dental, Legal &amp; Chaplain, Finance &amp; Contracting, and Special Investigations. Withing these categories, AFSCs are further assigned to "career fields." A career field may have one AFSC assigned to it, or it may have several. AFSCs with similar functions are grouped together in the same career field.</string>
    <string name="mos_home_detail">The United States Marine Corps\'s Military Occupational Specialty (MOS) is a system of categorizing career fields. All enlisted and officer Marines are assigned a four digit code denoting their occupational field and specialty.
            Occupational Fields (OccFlds) are identified in the first two digits and represent a grouping of related MOSs. Job codes are identified in the last two digits and represent a specific job within that OccFld. An MOS can be awarded as a Primary MOS (PMOS), an Additional MOS (AMOS), a Skill Designator, or Category II MOS (which denote special skills assignments or simply to account for structure when required).
            Below are listed the current authorized Marine Corps MOSs, organized by OccFld, then by specific MOS. Most MOSs have specific rank/pay grade requirements and are listed to the right of the MOS title, if applicable (see United States Marine Corps rank insignia), abbreviated from the highest allowed rank to the lowest. Officer ranks are noted as Unrestricted Line Officers[2] (ULOs), Limited Duty Officers(LDOs), and Warrant Officers(WOs). Those MOSs which are no longer being awarded are kept active to allow Marines to earn a new MOS.
            </string>

    <string name="army_home_detail">The United States Army uses various personnel management systems to classify soldiers in different specialties. Enlisted soldiers are categorized by their assigned job called a military occupational specialty, or MOS. Each MOS are labeled with a short alphanumerical code called a military occupational specialty code (MOSC), which consists of a two-digit number appended by a Latin letter. Related MOSs are grouped together by Career Management Fields (CMF). For example, an enlisted soldier with MOSC 11B works as an infantryman (his MOS), and is part of CMF 11 (the CMF for infantry).\n

Commissioned officers are classified by their area of concentration, or AOC. Just like enlisted MOSCs, AOCs are two digits plus a letter. Related AOCs are grouped together by specific branch of the Army or by broader in scope functional areas (FA). Typically, an officer will start in an AOC of a specific branch and move up to an FA AOC.\n

Warrant officers are classified by warrant officer military occupational specialty, or WOMOS. Codes consists of three digits plus a letter. Related WOMOS are grouped together by Army branch.

\n The Army is currently restructuring its personnel management systems. Changes took place in 2004 and will continue into 2013. Changes already taken place include deleting obsolete jobs, merging redundant jobs, and using common numbers for both enlisted CMFs and officer AOCs (e.g. "35" is military intelligence for both officers and enlisted).</string>


    <string name="navy_home_detail">The Navy Enlisted Classification (NEC) system supplements the rating designators for enlisted members of the United States Navy. A naval rating and NEC designator are similar to the Military Occupational Specialty (MOS) designators used in the U.S. Army and U.S. Marine Corps and the Air Force Specialty Code (AFSC) used in the U.S. Air Force.

The U.S. Navy has several ratings or job specialties for its enlisted members. An enlisted member is known by the enlisted rating, for example, a Machinist\'s Mate (or MM), and/or by the enlisted rate, for example Petty Officer First Class (or PO1). Often Navy enlisted members are addressed by a combination of rating and rate. In this example, this machinist\'s mate petty officer first class may be addressed as Machinist\'s Mate 1st Class (or MM1).</string>



    <string name="cg_home_detail">United States Coast Guard ratings are general occupations that consist of specific skills and abilities. Each rating has its own specialty badge, which is typically worn on the left sleeve of their service dress uniform by all enlisted personnel in that particular field. On Operational Dress Uniforms, they wear generic rate designators that exclude the rating symbol. Commissioned Officers do not have ratings.

\n Ratings should not be confused with "rates", which describe the Navy\'s and Coast Guard\'s enlisted pay-grades. Enlisted Navy and Coast Guardsmen are referred to by their rating and rate. For example, if someone\'s rate is Petty Officer 2nd Class and his rating is Boatswain\'s Mate; when combined, Boatswain\'s Mate 2nd Class (BM2) defines both.</string>
    <string name="title_activity_help">HelpActivity</string>

</resources>
